Shanna's why do you want to aim B and so
the idea of the ADEA Cafe is that he
defied any word is that we each take up
to five minutes to share our answer to
the question uninterrupted and then we
can have an open discussion after that I
think with these types of questions they
tend to go under five minutes
it doesn't necessarily get all the way
to the five minutes but I can start or
either of you concerns or you can pass
and just be part of the discussion as
well well a tea and I hate people
I'm agoraphobic so I've been like living
in an apartment by myself for since 2006
and retired completely from work since
2000 so I definitely needed a community
and game be just as wonderful the people
I mean YouTube Lee and Eric and everyone
has just been so beautiful toward me
well thank you I don't know whether was
that you're sharing or you see who is
gonna go first but that that was
beautiful that is like why you want game
be right that is your answer I think
that's that was really nice I found I
personally found that very touching
again it seemed really heartfelt so I
found that very touching and I must
admit that is an element of it for me as
well is a community of people that I can
actually talk about stuff I enjoy
talking about with because I do find
that in my own personal life there are
very few people willing to discuss ideas
of this nature any depth for any length
of time you know what I mean they want
to move on and talk about what whatever
the iPhone or Game of Thrones or
whatever it might be don't get me wrong
love getting influenced but anything but
yeah in a broader context why do I want
game this is it's funny because it
sounds like it's not personal but it but
it really is personal to me and I
couldn't possibly explain why but apart
from the obvious destructive nature of
the way we currently do things game a if
you wish to call it that you know the
environmental destruction the limiting
of people the subjugation of people the
massive inequality the 80% of people who
are you know struggling just to make
ends meet on a daily basis all of these
kind of things entirely unnecessary in
the light of modern understandings and
modern technologies you know and so and
and so there is all of that but but
worse than that even worse than that is
just the waste of human potential
because although we are agents of
unbelievable horror and destruction and
cruelty and whatever on this planet we
also have within us the capability for
unbelievable beauty and selflessness and
creativity and and all of this kind of
stuff right and so my hope for game be
for anything I mean it was the Venus
Project a few years ago in the zeitgeist
movement and actually there's a lot of
very very very close similarities in the
ideas but the the the the the shocking
waste that we are not already you know
exploring the other bodies in the solar
system and colonizing them you know to
me
we should have been doing those decades
ago instead of instead of which we're
still down here squabbling over who owns
wotton million Union Union yeah and it
just feels pathetic you know what I mean
it just feels pathetic and let's for
goodness sake move on and so game B
seems to me to be the most realistic
seed of something meaningful new
different that might start to embody
that hope that I have for Humanity
because it's grounded not in any
religious or political or ideological
kind of soil you know what I mean it's
independent of all of that and yet it
acknowledges the truth and the wisdom in
all of those things as well and
incorporates it into it you know what I
mean and so you know I always throughout
my whole life in the activist movement
I've been about trying to make
connections between oh you can't you see
that you're talking about the same thing
that they're talking about you're just
using different words but you're talking
about the same thing you know I mean and
so it's always been about that for me
and so yeah I think that that probably
sums it up pretty well thank you all
right um I wrote a little something
which I normally don't do but I was
having severe brain fog this morning and
so I was like in order to be able to
share I won't have to and then I'll go
from there it's not very long why I want
game B is that I'm not able to compete I
have health challenges and I feel like
I'm not able to compete within game a
but when my needs are met right now I
through disability I can contribute in a
unique and very amazing way and so I
want the abundance that we all create
together what Eric was talking about if
like unleashing humanity like we have so
much potential and I want all I want
access to all of that innovation I want
to give my gifts to the world in a way
that works for me and I want everyone to
be able to do that so that we can all
benefit from each other's work and art
and inventions and all of those things
and so much right now feels hard less
personally because I've kind of dealt
with that part of it
but globally just this like societal
pressure and then I can see how hurting
every it like all of these individuals
and families are that you don't have to
work 40 hours a week to pay for health
care or have to find health care or have
to just everything and I feel like we're
living in a dystopia and I know that
what is possible is something much
greater if like the smallest group of us
get together and start creating it and
it's never we don't create it with force
we don't you know create a new system
that everyone has to abide by but if we
create something so amazing then it's an
attractor that it's something that calls
other people in naturally because it can
mr. Rogers it which we were talking
before you went live like I love you for
who you are it is as like touchy-feely
as that sounds like the more we are able
to actually see each other and accept
each other for the diversity we
currently have the more we get
everybody's unique gift in the world
instead of everyone having to hide who
they are and everyone having to play
game a game B to me is a very diverse
and meeting people where they're at and
helping them figure out what they want
to give to the world and giving them the
tools to make that easy and fun and that
is what why I am part of game B and then
that piece you guys talked about which
is funny because I was like I wasn't
even thinking of that the game B
community it's amazing I'm so happy
about it because like Eric said finally
people to speak this conversation right
like finally people who want to speak
about how about creating a better world
I can see the crap that's wrong has been
seeing it since I was a kid but I like
and I want to talk about that too like
and that's a key so that people don't
want to talk about the bad stuff and
they also don't want to talk about
solutions they want like the government
to create solutions I'm like but they're
not going to like that be great but
they're not going to so can we can we
please create the solution so that is
why I want baby okay can I be first to
jump in here and just say in terms of
governments aren't going to do it can I
point you to none of the above as a
campaign first of all
the other thing which struck me as you
were talking which is something that is
also an important thing again be for me
but which I didn't talk about in mind
but you alluded to it was the individual
thing right and that another thing that
it's rooted in is making good people
right figuring out ways in which society
can be structured and organized so that
the the primary goal is the production
of good people because only with good
people can you make good sense and good
decisions right and so you know that
that that the emphasis on the
responsibility that every single node in
the network plays in the overall health
and vigor and so on of the network you
know what I mean I think I think that's
also a really crucial element of game B
it's not like it's it's not like an easy
thing it's not like a formula which oh
we just got to do that and everything's
gonna be all right every single person
has responsibility for improving
themselves to make themselves fit to be
a player of game B if you see what I
mean you know if that doesn't sound too
elitist because there is a danger of
that becoming a very elitist oh no
you're not qualified to play game B
you're not allowed to play that's a real
danger of that kind of thinking that's
what I'm qualifying it yeah I think for
me in community in like the physical
communities on part is in the real world
and online the biggest attractor or
determining factor and whether you fit
is if you want to fit right if you want
to play game B and you're willing to do
the inner work that's needed even if
you're failing at it that's that you
want to think that work or that you like
there's a big piece of what we need to
do for each other
the inner work is the Omega rule doing
the things that we need to do to be at
peace with ourselves we can be a piece
of other people but there's a bigger
piece we can kind of only solve as a
society which is like how do we feed
ourselves how do we close ourselves and
because everyone has to work 40 hours a
week to do that they're exhausted they
don't have time to start a revolution as
peaceful and easy as my one is
purporting to be like they're like but
I'm tired you do it you're like I can I
have a disability I'm doing what I can
and I'd yeah I don't remember what I'm
saying
brain fog is
pretty it's just usually that I'm I
can't ever get like a big picture of
society I'm just like a turtle is like
inside of a shell but when I started
when I was about seven to seventeen my
parents had a grocery store and I had to
go help whoever was driving the
groceries to somebody's home and
everybody left their door oh but all day
long even if they weren't home so I'd
have to go in to the apartment so I knew
I started knowing the intimate lives of
like two thousand people when I was
seven to seventeen and then in this
1970s I started working in their
so-called mental hospitals are places
where I believe people you know were
treated for just being disabled or
whatever so I I can't understand people
who realize when a third of the
population hardly ever and they're not
are the same people but it's
transmitting like the elderly the
disabled children there's always a third
of the people who are absolutely
helpless and a piece for that for me is
that I am one of those one-third people
like I can't work full-time
I can't even work pulsipher part-time in
game a because of all the restrictions
and what you need to do in order to do
that if you leave your house you have to
be on time you have to do certain things
that I can't do but when instead of
here's the box you have to fit into it I
get to create my own box I get to have
my needs met I get to make sure I show
up amazingly and you donate me like it's
it's I'm doing my piece it's i think
that one-third is a lot smaller than
one-third when we allow people to give
from where without it being a necessity
right not you're gonna starve if you're
not able to work but like what can you
give right can you look after children
children you know can you cut vegetables
like what is it the
that brings sparks joy that you want to
contribute and seeing their contribution
as worthy and not a deficiency right not
a less than you don't meet the bar so
you can't be part of it which it does
feel like extremely having a disability
like you're just seen as a drain on
society and I'm like I've never given
more to society than I'm currently
giving just not in the marketplace like
not in the way that society seems to
dictate it's a big problem Adam Adam
Smith identified this problem that there
are people who make enormous
contributions to the smooth functioning
of society whose contributions are not
monetizable he particularly used the
example of housewives right the
contribute they make is not easily
monetizable
I mean you know they a lot of housewives
got housekeeping back in the day didn't
they their husbands gave him 50 bucks a
week or whatever for housekeeping money
but yeah basically you know that the
contribution they make to the stability
of the home and the raising of the
children and the you know the
maintenance of the man's ability to you
know function in his job and all the
ironing his shirts and and all of that
kind of stuff that you know that was
that was part of the housewife's job
back in the day
even he ident even Adam Smith who was
supposed to be the father of modern
economics actually he's really
misunderstood anyway that's that's
another discussion even he said made
that point that it's it's the difference
between what's the word I had in my head
a minute ago when you were talking the
in between contribution and products it
no yeah productivity I know that's quite
the right word but you know being
productive and being a contributor these
are not the same things that being
productive is measurable monetizable
number Abul right whereas being
contributors everybody contributes in
all sorts of ways I mean he grants me he
never leaves the house right I bet you
he makes contributions in all sorts of
little wires to people around the place
you know I mean if if only online on you
know on the Facebook group or whatever
but you know that the
is one of the things about recognizing
the importance of connection right is
that every single thing that you do it
isn't just the immediate consequence of
the thing you do it's the consequences
of the consequences of the consequences
the consequences that ripple out through
eternity right you know that that's
that's that's the thing to bear in mind
yeah I like because the difference
between that productivity and never hurt
the other word is like one is your waves
you're like you know you're an Amazon
worker and how many things can you put
in a parcel per hour and anyone can be
that you're a cog in the machine whereas
your contribution is always very unique
no one else can do it and that's why
everyone's like well what if someone
just wants to sit around play video
games all day okay like you're telling
me they're talking they're having beers
with friends they're out playing sports
they're doing things that are like
they're gonna spark ideas and other
people when you're the person with the
idea you can't take all the credit for
it other people gave you art that
inspired you you know
drove the transport did everything for
you to be able to live your life like
we're so interconnected and it's both
pieces of that it's like you don't own
the thing just because you came up with
it you're not solely responsible for it
and everyone has something to give you
don't even know what you're giving right
you don't even know what you starts in
anyone else like you might be the person
sit around playing video games all day
and you feel like you're not
contributing but you are awesome I
donated like everyone's contributing for
me that it happened like around 1980 I
finally after 24 years got enough
credits for my BS and then I had to do a
lot of job hunting and that was about
the time that the American Disabilities
Act came in and I happened to be to see
how important that was that people with
the actual disability or condition or
whatever being in a position of power in
serving that population and it about
politics I happened my father's mentor
since childhood became a US congressman
so I got to know a lot about local
fixin national politics and what happens
in at least in our community what
happened a local politician the citizen
got into the office endless endless
amount of people coming in can you get
my daughter my niece my nephew my son
out of jail out of rehab you know
expecting some kind of miracle in human
psychology or something your point being
that what they were overwhelmed by stuff
they couldn't do anything about yeah
they're put into this like a golem a
monster statue that you know over over
people can possibly get what they think
they can from a simple human being who's
probably drunk all day long I got
socialized to be elected yeah I mean I
think okay so I think I might slightly
misunderstood your point so they're
being put in positions where they're
simply not able not qualified to do that
which is being asked of them right I
said just just yeah I can't even imagine
a person who can yeah yeah yeah
absolutely I think a huge part of what
we're dealing with is for like children
all of us who want our governments to
act on our behalf like they're our
parents when anyone has become a parent
know it was going on like he already
mean like it's like who's gonna adult
this oh it's me I have to I have to put
on an air of having my together so
my kid doesn't freak out and that's our
government's like they don't they don't
know what they're doing they've got no
but they put on this bravado this like
lendo we have to know what's going on we
have it under control don't worry
instead of us being honest like nobody
has an under control
nobody has the big picture we need to
create the big picture we need to
understand economics nobody understands
it economists look at something that
happens and then they then they pick it
apart nobody knows what happens in the
future because you have to add up all of
the like individual actions and people
don't they think what is the word in
economics like people are supposed to
act intelligently and they don't they
don't even have to know about interests
you can't even tell what they're gonna
act like and so little agent flexing in
their own best interests with perfect
information that's the assumption yeah
and we don't work in our own best
interest and we don't have perfect
information it's like the whole
foundation is nonsensical there are
there there is there is a new we had
we've mentioned this before I can't
member in what conversation but there is
another kind of economics emerging which
is based on exactly that that people
make irrational choices however their
irrationality is predictable right
they're irrational for very good reasons
and very sound reasons that are
universally irrational almost you know
what I mean and so that can be built
into the models and they're much much
much more accurate predictors of what
will actually take place in markets yeah
I mean I like actually asking the people
with understanding they don't actually
know right like what would you do in
exer compound's then give them excerpts
ants and see if it happens right like
would you buy your cornflakes from a
cooperative if we made them and they
cost as good and they were the same
price of course so they put in the money
and we make them and then it turns out
people don't want to well why why aren't
you now buying them right like looking
at like asking them making the system
around what they do say within reason
without the risk aren't like and then
and then when they don't cuz me said we
don't even know what we're gonna do
right like oh when I get my when I get
in a relationship when I have a kid when
I get my degree I'll be happy we're not
because we don't actually know what it's
like to get there and it's the same with
our buying power and everything else
like oh I was in this situation if I got
cancer I wouldn't do radiation or chemo
until you're there you don't know right
those are
wouldn't do it until you're there and
you don't know and so those you know
we're all perfect parents until we
become parents then it's a whole other
my kid will never do that until they do
answer you Eric about why why my
daughter and I agreed to be apart for
long periods of time she was like born
with some kind of intellectual Olympics
and I realized I could never contain
that you know she had to be on her own
somewhere in her community yeah it just
seems it seems like there's a middle
ground maybe somewhere you know what I
mean like not see each other for ten
years and being you know and and
stifling her it seems like somewhere in
between might be it might be a sweet
spot well for me I absolutely believe
Ruby's home you know there is a field
out there beyond right and wrong and
we're always there and I we agreed on
that when she was very young she
comprehended that all and I believe I
really believe we've always been there
together
I like that field beyond right and wrong
I like that I like that image feeling
mm-hmm
I think there is a lot there it's weird
because I'm in they're not opposite I'm
very like I'm a single parent to a child
and there's a lot that looks really bad
from the outside where I'm like right
this is how we function because of my
health limitations and just be an
introvert and being where like when I'm
present with her I try to give her like
you know half an hour to an hour of like
concentrated time David then I'm like I
need a long time and that's like you're
supposed to give yourself wholly over to
your kid I'm like and also just to put
your oxygen mask on first and how do you
combine those two especially as a mother
because the societal expectation is to
be a good parent you give your like
fully give yourself up I'm like but
that's not how I want her to parent I
don't want her to like get her needs met
until she's twenty thirty and then give
every cool self up to her children it's
about letting her emerge and letting
me emerge at the same time especially
when I didn't get that as a child and
figuring out that combination of like
our her needs Matt and I don't just mean
her food and clothing meets like does
she know she is loved in a deep down
level exactly who she is and yes but she
doesn't need me to play crafts with her
all day every day to know that my feet
like it's it's more about communicating
that and making sure that she she feels
that and it's I don't know that's what
then beyond right and wrong it's like
it's a feeling and me and her that it
works despite what the outside world
might judge it as and I know it judges
it yeah about knew I had a near-death
experience when I was about seven so
I've never felt that I'm looking at life
from inside my body and I have a new
friend who has tremendous amounts of
out-of-body experiences and I tried to
tell her like all physicality is like a
foreign language to me it has to be
interpret it because I want my own
intangible spiritual awareness to
identify Who I am
not my angry egotistical body can I just
go back to what you were saying a minute
ago Jubilee is a sort of change of
vocabulary occurred to me which could
sort of sort it all out because as you
said the societal expectation is that
you give yourself over hopefully to your
child right if you just change McHappy
very slightly put yourself as
effectively as you can in service of
your child all right yeah you cannot do
that unless you are meeting your own
needs right in the same way that if
you're a rescuer you don't put yourself
in danger if you're out there rescuing
other people right because if you now
have to be rescued as well you're just
an additional drain on the rescue
resources right so you know it's that
kind of principle you can't put yourself
in most full service of your child
unless your own needs are met so it is
not the two things are not in conflict
with each other as far as i concerned if
as I say you change the bikini I like I
like it because it's like internally
that's what it's like I had to get there
I had to get over through that that
feeling of like I'm
doing my child a disservice but now I'm
like in order to be a better parents I
had to become and this is not the right
for Kevin but like more selfish because
I'm a very selfless person in a very
like em path and all of these things
that mean that I want to make everyone's
needs met and then my needs weren't
getting met and it may be it's made me
physically ill and so looking after
myself has to be top priority or I'm not
gonna be around just to see her graduate
I'm not gonna be around to like be
physically present for her at all or
mentally or spiritually and so yeah I
like that I don't remember what language
was but it watch it if it's yeah that is
but yeah that rescuer and I've just been
saying like the the oxygen mask like cuz
even that like honestly you're looked at
as a bad parents like even though
everyone tells you to put the oxygen
mask on first on a plane like the actual
if you do it they're like oh but you
your instinct was it to put it on your
kid first
right cuz I'm logical if I pass out this
is bad I know that if she passes out I
can put it back on her and she'll be you
know okay in a moment which is the whole
reason of that was one lesson I learned
pretty early in my daughter's life is I
can't rescue her she has to be able to
risk yourself I could teach her that I'm
in New York model it continue she
learned to swim when she was three by
looking at a three year old friend that
she had named Cory Jack Wade's a little
redheaded girl and I saw that moment it
was at a YMCA pool and I saw my daughter
look at what Cory did which was to
actually swim you know like the
Australian crawl
Ramona into the pool together which was
only love babies
ten feet or something and she did it
right up right up about without even
thinking and then by the time she was
forced was jumping often the three meter
board into 16 feet of water and I was
hanging onto the edge of the pool I had
just learned this when I was thirty so
which is when she was about born so it's
impossible for me to rescue her from
anything she has to be tell her good
luck to do it yeah that our sense of
knowing that they can handle it is a big
piece of what we give them this sounds
like she's a super smart girl yeah like
most things in life actually it's a
double-edged sword yeah absolutely
absolutely it's true it's gonna say one
of the things about parenting we were
talking about your daughter is three
it's that it's like this 20 or
experiment and you don't know what the
outcome is until you're done and even
then you don't know if you had changed
anything whether it would actually
change the outcome or whether like you
have like its I kind of think the word
in science if like it's one experiment
right you're not repeating it and if you
have multiple kids even each one is its
own unique one and it's like well you
don't know like they can be completely
kind of be assholes as children or
teenagers and turn out really well or
perfect little angels until they're
adults and then not right and is that
the metric anyway of like how society
views them and how you know like for me
I want my kid to be happy
what other he/she has to define that she
has to figure that out I can't give that
to her I can't give her you'll be happy
if you're a doctor you'll be happy if
you marry rich no I know those are not
the two things that are gonna be the
defining factor if you're resilient if
you know you're enough if you can find
beauty in any situation that will make
you happy
hopefully we've been reporting for 30
minutes so I'm just gonna give everybody
a
chance to wrap up why do you want game
be and then we'll just say goodbye to
YouTube we can continue yeah I'd like it
to be there what my daughter hits bottom
because she's gonna need it yeah I don't
think I've really got anything so add
from what I said at the start you know
my my my hope is for a transformation
where the very worst parts of our nature
are those things which our society
incentivizes and rewards and a complete
flip around to that being the very best
parts of our nature that it's
incentivized and rewarded rewarded and
that allow one to achieve status and the
sender the what's it called the prestige
hierarchy or the prestige hierarchy
starts to dominate the dominance
hierarchy the dominance hierarchy falls
away as being meaningless and irrelevant
and archaic and out-of-date and you
ascend the prestige hierarchy through
the value of the contributions that you
make right you know it's not about
celebrity it's not about publicity it's
not about making speeches it's about the
actual value of the contribution that
you make and because you have sovereign
educated discerning population they are
able to tell the difference between an
actual contribution and a
contribution you know what I mean and so
now this is this is the kind of work you
know where this is yeah I'm gonna start
repeating myself so stop there that's
like all I do I probably don't have too
much to add either I am creating game be
like I think we're all working towards
creating it in our purse in my personal
life and my relationships in platonic
play game a as little as possible and
yet knowing that the more I'm willing to
play it possibly the faster I can move
towards game B but I just can't anymore
once you know I just can't a tane wealth
when I know what that costs the rest of
the world and dealing with my own my own
game B as best as possible which is I
would there was something you had said
that I wanted to add which was this idea
that we just like right now game a it's
definitely proposed like holds up
rewards horrible behavior and it gave me
I would also like to see the opposite
but I think even more than that I want
us to allow the whole individual that
possibly what is our shadow sides or
what is our challenges is part of us and
so if instead of just be hot like even
that prestige even like being able to
contribute at a higher level is itself a
gift and therefore like you've already
kind of won the gift like you've already
kind of won the rewards someone else who
has it unlike a harder challenge or or a
bigger dark side to overcome might have
something different to give that isn't
going to bring with it prestige but it's
very much needed in the world and so I'm
just gonna say goodbye to YouTube now